## **BUSINESS SYSTEMS ANALYST**

Summary

Highly efficient Business Analyst with 8+ years of experience in Business Analysis, Business Intelligence, Software Development, Software Testing, Decision Analytics, Product Management, Software Lifecycle, Market Research and Technology Strategy Experience in working with customer satisfaction driven environment, encourages to be more comprehensive in deriving creative ideas which help in achieving business objectives Proficiently worked as a liaison between Business and IT partners, Efficiently created Test Documentations, Test Plans, Test Scenarios, Test Cases, Software Requirement Specifications and Test scripts Experienced in Requirements Gathering and Analysis, authoring Business Requirements documents, Functional Requirements documents, User stories, preparing and executing Project plans Full software lifecycle experience using both Waterfall and Agile/Scrum methodologies Experienced in User Experience (UX), User Interface Design (UI), and Client Management. Worked on industry leading Business Intelligence tools such as Tableau, SQL, MS excel and knowledge on Qlikview, SAS. Highlights

Proficiency in Tableau ,UML, Use Cases, Qlikview ,Rally, HP Quality Center , SharePoint, MS SQL, MySQL, UNIX, Linux, Oracle, SAS, MS Office, MS Visio, MS Project, MS Access, MS Excel.

## **Accomplishments**

Boosted customer service ratings by 80 % by developing new processes and improving work flow. Increased cost-effectiveness by 60 % through compliance enforcement and implementation of a new quality control system.

Experience

Flex November 2015 to June 2016 Business Systems Analyst

Austin, TX

- Experienced in working cross-functionally to drive ideas from conception to execution, defining and analyzing success metrics, managing strategic projects and business owner of the solutions.
- My current project emphasizes on the customers satisfaction, where our audience are our customer representatives.
- They are the voice of FedEx to the world, we as team work pro-actively to provide a worry-free system by deriving various measures using Performance Guard, which can identify possible system breakdowns and keep us informed about the health of the systems.
- Envisaged and Developed Performance Guard solution to proactively identify, track and manage system outages.
- There by improving Ticket resolution time by 40% as compared previous resolution standards.
- Designed dashboards and created Interactive Data Analytics solution using Tableau to analyze incoming data in request tracker, Created Performance Metrics, and Benchmark Scorecard evaluating the Team performance.
- The tool helped executives gain actionable insights.
- Contributed in Retuning Request Tracker along with technical team to ensure the Data was captured correctly, this a channel where Customer reps raise tickets if the workstation they are using is not working as expected.
- Analyzed and improved reporting Standards for Virtual Assistance Solution using Tableau.
- The new reports will help the team to ensure FCR (First Call Resolution) is provided by VA avoiding the transfer of call to Chat Rep.
- This might result in additional cost to company towards hiring more resources.
- Working as a Business Stakeholder for PDSM project (Process Driven System Management), representing DPI as end user, collecting requirements for the team, to aid the smooth transition from existing Request tracker.

Iheartmedia, Inc. April 2012 to September 2015 Senior Business Analyst Kansas City

- Business goal of the project was to ease the ATM related complaints registered due to failed transactions.
- We Developed a system where disputed transactions were registered by our branches using the Unique Transaction ID's and the details of that Transaction ID were captured in our CBS system, reducing the possibility of lodging the wrong case and ensuring the timely action on the complaints.
- This helped us to adhere to the time frames set by Reserve Bank of India in resolving cardholder grievances.
- Failing which there was a penalty which was imposed to Card issuer if the dispute was not resolved within particular timeframe.
- Worked closely with customer satisfaction oriented business teams and contributed in various Policy matters to ensure the business objectives are achieved.
- Prepared business requirements document for the project by meeting Stakeholders and development teams.
- Identified customer needs, outlined requirements and integrated cutting edge Transaction reconciliation solutions and concepts, resulting 50% increase in customer satisfaction within 1 year.
- Designed an effective system by making use of Core Banking System (CBS) technology for resolving ATM transaction disputes as per the guidelines set by NFS, VISA and MasterCard, these disputes varies from double debit to wrong debit in the account due to system failure/technical glitch.
- Cardholders face this hurdle when they use ATMs.
- This system gave a good platform by capturing right failed ATM transaction, which helped in registering the actual transaction in dispute, this effectively reduced the complaint resolution time by 80% over the traditional method.
- Worked on determination of key information and analysis requirements to build supporting Information and decision support systems.
- Created systems plans matched to business requirements and build performance measurement of value creation.
- Analyzed huge data both qualitatively and quantitatively, modeled multitier re-rating system and reconciled complex financial transactions.

Optech August 2007 to April 2012 Business Analyst Minneapolis

As a college fresher, I got an opportunity to work with great teams, who pioneered in launching new products to the new evolving market,

understanding the customer needs.

- Several products like International Credit card, Travelers card, Prepaid Cards and Insta Debit cards were launched during this period, which set our institution to all new heights in the Indian banking sector.
- Created Interactive Business Intelligence platform for Bank customers.
- Conducted market research and product line analysis to establish detailed solutions design.
- Product Line Management, Analyzed business needs, documented requirements, and provided necessary inputs to the Development and Testing team for execution Designed and created use cases and UML diagram's, from the BRD (Business requirement document), worked closely with the testing and development teams to ensure the goal was met without any delay.
- Captured the various requirements of stakeholders and best possible attempts were made to deliver the product as described to the user.
- Working along with technical team, where we designed and deployed the EMV compliance as per VISA standards which was a mandate to ensure the cardholders information was protected from skimming.
- Applied various testing best practices to ensure end to end accuracy of business transactions and Validated operational and financial completeness and accuracy 2.

## Education

Manipal University Feb 2012 Master of Business Administration (MBA): Banking & Finance City, India Banking & Finance Bachelor of Engineering: Computer Science City, India Computer Science

May 2007 NMIT

Skills

ATM, banking, Business Intelligence, business owner, Credit, customer satisfaction, Debit, decision support, edge, financial, HP, hiring, Linux, managing, market research, market, MS Access, MS Excel, MS Office, MS Project, SharePoint, MySQL, NFS, Oracle, Quality, reporting, requirement, SAS, MS SQL, strategic, Tableau, team work, UML, Unique, UNIX, Visio